Elisabeth C Gray

elcgray@gmail.com 317-435-1257 http://elisabethgray.me/cv

I have fifteen years of experience in technical roles across service, educational, and financial technology industries. Within these roles, I've focused on improving the means by which people relate, communicate, and interact with each other.

In both my professional and academic work, I am driven by a deep-set interest in the macro-to-micro relationships between society and technology, particularly with regard to media technology's role in the definition of cultural identity and the propagation and mitigation of conflict.

Education

M.S., Global Technology and Development, 2015

Arizona State University, School for the Future of Innovation in Society

B.S., Media Arts and Science with Distinction, 2005

Indiana University, School of Informatics

Concentration: Journalism

Minor: French

Certificate coursework: Computer Science

Honors: Deans List (2000-2005), Merit Recognition Scholarship, Outstanding Freshman Scholarship, Honors Scholarship, Scholastic Achievement Scholarship, School of Informatics Student Council (President), Undergraduate Student Assembly (Senator, Grievance Committee Secretary)

Competencies

Skills

Apple hardware, Apple iOS, Apple OS, BibTeX, continuous integration (CI), customer relationship management, customer support, CSS, data analysis, database management, data visualization, digital media creation, digital publishing, educational assessment, English (native written, spoken), French (written, spoken), Git, HTML, JavaScript, knowledge management, Markdown, people management, print publishing, project management, research, Ruby, Sass, server administration, SQL, student information administration, technical writing, troubleshooting, video editing, Windows

Tools

Adobe Creative Suite (Acrobat, Illustrator, InDesign, Lightroom, Photoshop, Premiere Pro), Asana, Atlassian Confluence, Atom, Chrome DevTools, Command Prompt, Desk.com, Facebook for Developers, FileMaker Pro, Final Cut Pro, Garageband, Github, Google Analytics, Google for Education, Google Scholar, Google Suite, Google Web Tools, Grunt, Gulp, IBM SPSS, iMovie, iTerm, iWork (Keynote, Numbers, Pages), Jekyll, Jekyll-Scholar, Jenkins, JSTOR, LexisNexis, Liquid, Mac OS Terminal, MediaWiki, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint), Node, NPM, NWEA MAP assessments, Open Access Journals, PBworks, PowerSchool, Rails, Salesforce, Sequel Pro, Travis CI, Trello, TweetTracker, Twitter Analytics, Xcode

Experience

Braintree

Braintree is a financial technology company that specializes in mobile and web payment systems for ecommerce. It was acquired by PayPal in 2013.

Knowledge Product Manager Chicago, IL | 2017-present

The documentation team was retitled and restructured to better reflect its contributions to the company. Responsibilities remain the same as those detailed below.

Knowledge Management Lead Chicago, IL | 2013-2017

I founded Braintree's documentation team and designed it as a cross-organizational structure responsible for the company's internal policy and procedure as well as its technical and non-technical support content.

My role is focused on liaising with product, operations, and leadership teams to determine new documentation needs and identify new opportunities for collaboration with multi-location teams on technical initiatives to consistently improve documentation content, accessibility, and functionality. One of my largest public projects was a multi-phased release of a new documentation structure for Braintree support content, including:

- The reorganization of existing developer content
- The introduction of a <u>server-side reference</u>
- The release of a new non-technical support article site

I am also responsible for designing and implementing methods for syncing large repositories of shared content between separate organizations within the company.

Ops Specialist Chicago, IL | 2012-2013

I co-led the development of Braintree's intranet using Atlassian Confluence with the lead product engineer. I was responsible for migrating existing content into the new structure and managing Confluence user setup, permissions management, plugin installation, and updates. Prior to the project's rollout, I implemented new processes and procedures related to content management and led training sessions on the new tool. I also helped author internal and public-facing content. Finally, I managed Operations process development and knowledge management for the first joint product release as a subsidiary of PayPal.

Integration Support Specialist Chicago, IL | 2011-2012

My initial role's focus was on helping merchants and developers integrate with Braintree's application program interface (API). As part of a small company of less than 40 people, I also created a standardized computer image prior to the establishment of a dedicated IT team in order to help onboard new employees more quickly and consistently and led an initiative to create Braintree's first public-facing support article content for a less technical audience.

University of Chicago Charter School

The University of Chicago Charter School is a neighborhood charter school on Chicago's South Side, operated by the University of Chicago Urban Education Institute.

Technology Director Chicago, IL | 2009-2011

In addition to the responsibilities of the Tech Support Specialist, I organized and facilitated a 1:1 technology program using Apple products for 600 students and staff, designed policy and procedure, managed asset maintenance and distribution, developed and administered training sessions for teachers and students, and reconciled the technology budget and reduced the technology loss rate on campus from 36% to 3.69% by 2009 and to 0.71% by 2011.

Tech Support Specialist Chicago, IL | 2008-2009

This role focused on repairing broken technology, managing computer deployment, facilitating computer-based assessments (e.g. NWEA MAP tests), and performing server maintenance. I also designed a class to teach students technical troubleshooting and repair.

Apple Inc.

Apple Inc. is a technology company that designs, develops, and sells consumer electronics, computer software, and online services.

Mac Genius Chicago, IL | 2006-2008

As a Mac Genius, I diagnosed and repaired computer hardware and software issues, educated customers on computer maintenance and troubleshooting, and trained new employees.

Visual Specialist Indianapolis, IN | 2003-2006

I managed software versions and hardware upgrades for front and back of house operations.

Gold Wing Touring Association

Gold Wing Touring Association is an international not-for-profit organization of touring motorcyclists.

Media and Marketing Manager Indianapolis, IN | 2002-2004

I designed, organized, and edited the non-profit association's monthly magazine, negotiated and communicated with advertisers and printers, and developed marketing, advertising, and media plans.

Projects

Presentations

What Do Our Docs Say About Us? 2016

Co-presented at an internal product conference with over 500 attendees, examining the company's internal and external documentation as an anthropological and sociological artifact of who Braintree is and what its employees value.

Documentation Domination: How to Build a Knowledge Sharing Culture in 4 Easy Steps 2015

Co-presented at Atlassian Summit, a knowledge management conference with over 2,500 attendees, sharing observations on how to improve collaboration and communication across teams and internal organizations using Atlassian Confluence as a knowledge management platform.

Out of Sight 2005

Researched and designed a video documentary on homeless youth in Indianapolis, Indiana. Defended research, production, and findings of the capstone project to a panel of faculty and peers and then facilitated a viewing and question-and-answer session on the research, production, and findings of the project.

Papers

Social Media and the Arab Uprisings 2015

Designed and implemented a structured research plan for delivering 14 original articles on the role of social media in the Arab Uprisings in Tunisia, Egypt, and Libya.

Information Warfare: The Roles of Social Media in Conflict 2014

Argued that the power of media to provoke or abate conflict is historically significant and that social media is following in the footsteps of its predecessors, but the speed at which it can gain momentum makes it an especially sharp double-edged sword.

<u>Building Fences: Saudi Arabia's Strategy for National Security</u> 2014

Observed that the Saudi government's focus on defending its borders to improve security may be an oversight, that its greatest potential threat likely comes from within, and that events occurring in the surrounding area could significantly increase tension.

<u>Se Va a Poner Feo: The Culture of Violence in Mexico and Its Impact on Development Efforts</u> 2014 Explored the relationship between cultures of violence and the status of development efforts in those areas most significantly affected by conflict.

Never Again? The US Response to Genocide in Bosnia and Rwanda 2013

Reflected on the United States' response to signs of genocide in Bosnia and Rwanda in the 1990s.